provbank.com 2001-12-16

# Provident Bank's Online Privacy Policy

* * *

**Provident Bank's Customer Privacy Policy**

At Provident Bank and its subsidiaries, our focus on each customer relationship is responsiveness to your needs. We recognize that you have chosen to do business with our company because we provide superior quality products and service to meet your financial objectives. We also recognize that you expect and trust the Bank to safeguard personal and financial information. Protecting customer information and maintaining the confidentiality and integrity of the information is something we take very seriously. We believe that your privacy should be maintained. We also want to offer you the array of financial products and services you need to accomplish your financial goals. The Bank believes that we can do both, as described in this privacy policy. 

**Customer Information We Collect**

Information about our customers comes from a variety of sources. Some information is provided to the Bank directly by our customers. Other information is developed by us as a function of providing a product or service to our customers. Customer information is also obtained from outside sources, e.g., credit bureaus. We will limit the collection of information about our customers to that which is necessary to administer our business, provide superior service, and offer opportunities that we believe will be of interest to you. 

**Use of Customer Information**

The Bank will use and retain information about our customers only for specific business and legal purposes - and we will tell you, upon request, why we are collecting and retaining such information. This means that we will use customer information to protect and administer your records, accounts and funds; to comply with certain laws and regulations; and to help us design and improve our products and service to you. 

**Sharing Customer Information**

From time to time, we share customer information with our subsidiaries in accordance with the Bank's confidentiality policies and this Customer Privacy Policy. We also share customer information under the following circumstances: (1) where a customer consents to the disclosure; (2) where we are legally required or allowed to do so; and (3) where it is necessary to process or service your transaction with us. 

**Security of Customer Information**

We continually strive to keep customer information accurate, secure, and confidential. We pledge to respond to your requests to correct inaccurate information in a timely manner. The Bank's confidentiality and business ethics policies provide, among other things, that all customer information is considered private and privileged. Employee access to customer information is limited to those individuals with a business reason to know such information. The Bank's operational and data processing systems are in a secure environment that prohibits customer account information from being accessed by unauthorized third parties. 

**Third Party Relationships**

From time to time, the Bank may contract with third parties to perform banking and customer service functions on the Bank's behalf. When we provide customer information to such parties, the Bank requires \- generally through a written agreement - that the third parties adhere to privacy principles similar to those to which Provident adheres for keeping customer information confidential. We do not provide customer information to unaffiliated companies for the purpose of independent telemarketing or direct mail marketing of non - financial products or services. 

**Medical Information**

The Bank does not share medical or health information among our family of companies, except to provide services that you have requested or initiated. 

**Provident Bank Commitment**

Provident Bank and its employees value our customer relationships. We want you to understand how we use the information you provide to us and our commitment to ensuring your personal privacy. Customers who have questions about this Customer Privacy Policy or have questions about the privacy or accuracy of their customer information should call us at 1-800-962-9644 or within the Baltimore area, 410-281-7111, or e-mail us at feedback@provbank.com. 

**Simple Steps to Safeguard Your Identity**

"Identity theft" involves the theft of an individual's personal information. Those involved in identity theft typically assume an individual 's identity, apply for credit in his or her name, run up bills, do not pay creditors and often damage the victim's credit record. 

At Provident Bank, we have instituted a combination of safeguards to protect customers. These safeguards include employee training, rigorous security standards, data encryption and fraud detection. In addition, you can also personally take these additional steps to deter identity theft:

  * Do not give your Social Security or account numbers to anyone over the telephone unless you initiated the call.
  * Tear up receipts, old bank statements and unused credit card offers before throwing them away. Such information can be retrieved from your trash and used to obtain credit in your name. 
  * Review your bank and credit card statements as soon as you receive them to check for unauthorized transactions. 
  * Protect your PINs and computer passwords, use a combination of letters and numbers, and change them often. Never carry this information with you! 
  * Order copies of your credit report once a year to ensure accuracy. Call any of the three national credit reporting agencies: Trans Union (800) 888-4213, Equifax (800) 685-1111, or Experian (888) 397-3742 to request a copy of your report. 
  * Report any suspected fraud to your bank and credit account companies immediately so that they can take appropriate steps to prevent or stop identity theft. .
